赤焰战场
社会安全码943662291
Nine four three six six two two nine one.
请转养老金服务处
Pension services, please.
谢谢,莫西斯先生,请等候代表
Thank you, Mister Moses, please hold for your representative.
嗨,我是莎拉
Hi, this is Sarah.
我是法兰克莫西斯
It's Frank Moses.
嗨,法兰克,怎么了？
Hey. Frank. What's goin' on？
小事
Not much.
我打来因为他们又没寄支票
I just called because they didn't send that check out again.
他们居然到现在还没搞定
I can't believe…they haven't worked this out by now.
我会确定他们今天再寄一份
I'll make sure they send another one out today.
非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
真没辄呢
Well, what are you gonna do？
你的鳄梨树长得怎样？
So how's your avocado？
长出两片绿叶
It's got two green leaves on it.
太好了,我早建议你种些植物
Yay！ I told you you could grow something.
树险些挂掉,生死一瞬间
Well… It was pretty close. It was life or death.
不唬人,非生即死
I'm not kidding.
你今天好吗？
It coulda gone either way. How's your day going？
我今天？我今天糟透了
My day. My day sucks.
你今天糟透了？
Your day sucks？
对
Yeah.
目前我只想旅行
Right now I just want to travel, you know？
我在考虑智利
I'm thinking Chile.
听起来很冒险,或许吧
Sounds like an adventure.
你去过智利吗？
I don't know. You ever been to Chile？
去过
Yeah.
真的？那里怎样？
You have？ Well, what's it like？
多山
Mountains.
就这样？
That's it？
当时是晚上,我…
Well, it was night, I, I'm-
那时…
It was, uh…
听着,我得挂了
Look, I gotta go.
好,当然
Uh, um, oh, I …okay, sure.
糟糕,葛拉蒂丝在监督
No, no, sorry, it's just Gladys.
什么？
What？
“当时是晚上”
“It was night.”
嗨,莫西斯先生！
Hi, Mister Moses！
嗨
Hi.
你开始读那本新书了吗？
Did you start that new book？
对
I did.
书名叫什么？
And？ What's it called？
叫作“爱情的残酷秘密”
Uh, it's called “Love's Savage Secret”.
水喔
Nice.
写得好吗？
Is it any good？
超白烂,我就爱这种芭乐书
It's terrible. I love it.
描述一名时装设计师 以及他的超模马子
Awful. It's…about this, this fashion designer and his,
他们被中情局招募
his supermodel girlfriend and they get recruited by the CIA
要阻止米兰春装秀的刺杀行动
to stop an assassination at the Milan spring shows.
谁不爱春天的米兰呢？
Well… Who doesn't like Milan in the spring？
大概吧
I guess.
反正我得找些乐子
Anyway, I gotta do something for excitement.
我的房东太太一直想…
My landlady keeps trying to
撮合我跟她牌友的小孩
set me up with her bridge partners' kids.
她刚告诉我她以为我是拉拉
She just told me she thinks I'm gay.
我尽量不予置评
I try not to judge.
什么？闭嘴！我不是拉拉
What？ Shut up！ I'm not gay.
有件事很突然
So here's something weird.
我其实下周要去堪萨斯城
I'm actually gonna be in Kansas City next week.
相见欢？
In person.
对
Mm hm.
天啊,这可能是个坏主意
Wow. That could be a bad idea.
可能
It could be.
你还在吗？
You still there？
还在
Yeah. Yeah.
你到当地再打给我吧
Why don't you call me when you get to town？
或者…好吧
Or… Yeah.
好,拜
'Kay. Bye.
Okay, bye.
好
Okay.
很好
Alright.
“爱情的残酷秘密”
回答,第一单位
Come in, Unit One.
第一单位,快回应
Unit One, respond.
堪萨斯城
不邀我进去吗？
Whoa！ Hey, aren't you going to invite me in？
不,我想不了
No, I don't think so.
可是我给你买单了晚餐
Uh, but I bought you dinner！
天啊
Wow！ Wow.
Wow.
你跟母亲一起住呢
And you live with your mother.
逊毙了
Awesome.
当然了,你失业
Yeah, of course. You have no job.
你这烂人,别想得逞
You, Mister, are not getting any of this.
嗨
Hey.
是我,法兰克
It's me. Frank.
鳄梨树？
The avocado？
你怎么在这里？滚出我家！
Why are you here？ Get out of my house！
我叫你先打电话来
- Hey！ - I told you to call first.
我不会伤害你
I'm not gonna hurt you.
听我说好吗？拜托？
Would you just listen to me？ Please？
住手
Stop that！
后退,别靠近我
Get back. Go away！ Stay away from me！
那是我的行李？
Is that my bag？
对
Yeah.
你打包的？
You, you packed it？
对
Yes.
你有吸地板？
Did, did, did you vacuum？
稍微清一下,这里很乱
A little, yeah, it was messy.
后退,滚出去
- Get back. Get out. - Please.
拜托,我们得快闪人,住手
- Get out. Get out！ - We have to leave. - Get out！ - Right now. Stop it.
救命！救命！
- Help！ - Hey！ Just listen to me, please.
有人想杀我
- Help！ - Someone is trying to kill me. - Help！ Intruder！ -What are you doing？
你在干嘛？听我说
- Listen to me！ - Help！
他们也想杀你
They've been trying to kill you, too.
为什么有人想杀我？
Why would anyone want to kill me？
因为我们受到监控
Because we've been under surveillance.
有人一直监听我们的电话
They've been listening to our conversations.
为什么？
Why？
因为我对你说话的方式
Because of the way I talk to you.
什么？
What？
他们知道我喜欢你
They know I like you.
听我说,马上从后门出去
Listen to me. Right now.
免谈！不要！
- Out the back door. Right now！ - No way！ No！
别误会我,我知道这很疯狂
Don't get me wrong, I know it's crazy.
别以为我不吃惊
Don't think that, that I don't think this is, this is crazy.
这也…
And
完全不符合…
it couldn ' t be more different
我希望与你初次见面的情况
than how I'd hoped to meet you for the first time.
不过天有不测风云
But, you know, sometimes things happen.
我希望有一天我和你能…
And I just hope that someday you and I could be…
惬意地坐在某处
sitting somewhere,
回想这一切,当作一次伟大冒险
comfortably and look back on this as the, the great big adventure that it is.
我也有点饿,要吃什么？
I'm a little hungry, too. What should we get？
披萨
Pizza.
听着,亲爱的
Listen, hon.
许多男孩在学校被欺侮
Yeah, lots of boys get bullied at school.
我知道,但你不能硬插手解决
I know, but you just, you can't solve it by intervening like that.
不,我不苟同你的想法
No, I don't agree with you.
我懂,这很难
I know, I know, it's hard.
我回家会找他谈
I'll, I'll talk to him about it when I get home. Mm hmm.
不,我今晚应该会准时到家
No, I should be on time tonight.
买低脂牛奶,好,爱你,拜
Milk, two percent？ Okay, love you, bye.
听着,我能让你富有
Listen. I can make you rich.
你不知道我是什么角色？
Don't you know who I am？
我当然知道
Course, I do.
“10分钟后碰面,威尔克斯”
这任务不公开,完全非官方
This is off the books. Total blackout.
是,女士
Yes, ma'am.
这是你的目标
There's your target.
退休分析员,前中情局探员
Retired analyst. He was CIA.
有问题吗？
Is that a problem？
没有
No.
纽奥良
抱歉
Sorry.
如果你放我走,我不会告你
Wow. If you, if you let me go now, I won't press charges.
别伤和气
There's no hard feelings.
我们不受控告保护
We're way past charges.
我怎么老是吸引你这种逊人？
How do I always attract losers like you？
我是前中情局探员
I was in the CIA.
那敢情好,你是间谍咧
Yeah, I bet you were. I'll bet you're a spy.
我现在要去见某人
I have to go see someone now-
你打算让我被绑在这里？
You're just gonna make me sit here？ Like this？
这样最安全,没人知道你在这里
You couldn't be safer. No one knows where you are.
不,别这样
Oh, no, you don't- Don't do it.
别乱动
You don't- Please… - Just hold still. -I, I don't want it.
不要…
- Don't- Oh- Um.
对不起…
Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry.
你的眼睛很美
Your eyes are so beautiful.
想看电视吗？
Want to watch TV？
很快回来
Be back soon.
那玩意又出毛病吗？
Is that thing acting up again？
嗨,玛娜
Oh. Hi, Marna, yeah. Hi.
敲一下,看能不能替我弄好
Give it a rap, will ya？ See if you could get it going for me.
当然
Oh, of course.
我不懂为什么你不修好这老古董
I don't know why you don't fix this old thing.
给你修更养眼
Better picture.
天线移左边一点
Try a little bit more to the left.
好
Okay.
好耶
Yeah.
太赞了
That's just…perfect.
感激不尽,玛娜
Thank you very much, Marna.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
真不要脸
Should be ashamed of yourself.
很高兴见到你,小子
It's nice to see you, kid.
我也是
It's good to see you, too.
什么事？
So…what's up？
认识个美眉
Met a girl.
不会吧
No.
很复杂
Complicated.
一群杀手造访
Got a visit from a wet team.
在我家,24小时前
At my house, twenty-four hours ago.
你能辨认他们任何人吗？
D'you ID any of 'em？
算吧
Kinda.
以前混江湖没这么野蛮
This used to be a gentleman's game.
我爱你,拜
And you know I love you. Bye.
独立的南非职业杀手团
Independent South African hit team
涉嫌杀害一名纽约时报记者
suspected of killing a New York Times reporter.
陈史蒂芬妮,认识她吗？
Stephanie Chan. You know her？
不认识
No.
有人硬是杠上你呢,小子
Somebody has a serious hard-on for you, kid.
是啊
Yeah.
但挑现在干嘛？我退休了
But why now？ I'm retired.
还得多打听
Just have to dig some more.
你也要留意
Watch your back, too.
我80岁,罹患肝癌末期
I'm eighty years old, I got stage four liver cancer.
他们能拿我怎样？
The hell can they do to me？
他们还是能射杀你
They can still shoot you.
说真的…
Well…
我从没料到我会落得这种下场
I never thought this would happen to me.
什么？
What？
变老
Getting old.
越南、阿富汗
Well, I mean, Viet Nam. Afghanistan.
绿泉养老院？
Green Springs Rest Home？
真想不到
Go figure.
莫西斯打到养老金服务处22次
So Moses made twenty-two calls to pension services
不觉得可疑？
and that didn't stand out to you？
匪夷所思
Unbelievable.
“有效急救电话”
中奖了
Hooh-rah.
叫恩迪科特去卡布里饭店…
Have Endercott intercept
拦截那女人
the girl at the Hotel Capri.
麦克,计划改变
Hey, Mike, change of plans.
她没事
She's just fine.
我能带你回家
I can take you home. Oh.
但我得先带你去警局做笔录
I gotta take you down to the station first to get your statement.
然后几位调查局人员想跟你谈话
And then there's a couple of federal guys that are gonna want to talk to you.
你挣脱并保持镇静令人佩服
I gotta say I think you're pretty amazing for, uh, breaking free and keeping it together like you did.
勇气可嘉
That's impressive.
我要回去拿我的钱包
Um, I've, I'm gonna go back and get my purse.
我能找人替你拿来
Oh, I can have somebody bring it downtown for you.
没关系
- No, it's okay, I'll just…
上车！
- Get in the car！
放开我,你弄痛我了
Ow！ Let me go！ You're hurting me.
我会死吗？
Am I gonna die？
不,你只是需要眯一下
No. Just need some sleep.
我可能会吐
I may vomit.
好像在演“爱情的残酷秘密”呢
Wow, this is just like “Love's Savage Secret”.
我好High
I am high.
你的绿眼珠很美
You have such beautiful green eyes.
你真的是中情局探员呢
Wow. You really are CIA.
警官倒下,北彼得和康提街交界
Officer down. Corner of North Peters and Conti.
嫌犯是白人男性,三十几岁
Suspect is a white male, thirties,
黑西装打领带,开黑色休旅车
black suit and a tie, driving a black Tahoe.
别动！快把武器放地上！
Freeze！ Put your weapon on the ground！
快放地上！
Put your weapon on the ground now！
扔掉武器！
Get it down there！ Get it on the ground now！ Drop the gun！ Right now！
你说这是中情局批准的行动？
So you're saying this was CIA sanctioned？
黛玛,谢了,欠你个人情,拜
Alright, Thelma, thanks, I owe you one. Bye.
就这回事？
So it's like that, huh？
对,就这回事
Yeah. It's like that.
我们在哪里？
Where are we？
我们怎么会来纽约市？
Ho-how did we get to New York City？
我现在真的讨厌你了
Wow, I really hate you right now.
我希望你能稍微体谅这种局面
I was just hoping you'd be a little more understanding of the situation.
我希望不要被绑架,或被下药
Uh, I was hoping not to get kidnapped.
我希望你不是秃头
Or drugged. I was hoping you'd have hair.
看来我们的梦想都无法当下实现
So it looks like none of our dreams are comin' true, at the moment.
很遗憾
Sorry about that.
我该说谢谢救我吧
Thanks for…saving me. I guess.
别客气
No problem.
称不上我最棒的初次约会
Not my best first date.
也不算最鸟的
Not my worst. Either.
查出谁想杀我们之前
Until we find out who's trying to kill us,
我们得一起行动
you're gonna have to stay with me.
多久？
For how long？
我不知道
I don't know.
想杀我们的人
Whoever's trying to kill us
也杀了一名纽约时报记者
also killed a New York Times reporter.
她住过中国城
She used to live in Chinatown.
到了,过来进来,等一下
Okay, okay. Here we go. Let's come in here. Right here. Wait a second here.
拿着这些胶带
You just hang onto this tape.
不,你说我们只是要跟她谈话
Oh no. No, you said we were just gonna talk to her.
对,但用得上
We are. This'll help.
那女人刚失去女儿
The woman just lost her daughter.
你不行到哪里都用胶带绑人
I know. You can't just go around duct taping everyone.
人们基本上都算好人
People are basically kind of decent.
我的经验看来不尽然
That hasn't always been my experience.
让我试着跟她谈话
- Let me try and talk to her.
什么？
- What？
让我来就是了
Just let me, let me do it.
他们要我有耐心
They told me to be patient.
警方毫无进展
The police have done nothing.
他们说只是窃盗案
They said it was just a burglary,
但没东西被偷
but, but nothing was missing.
她很害怕
She was scared.
我们希望能查明更多真相
We're hoping we can do more.
你是我女儿的同事？
You worked with my Stephanie？
她寄给我这个
She sent me this.
她死的那天我收到这邮件
I got it in the mail on the day she died.
这是什么意思？
What does this mean？
我不知道
I don't know.
我试打过这号码
I tried dialing the numbers.
警方也不知道
Police had no idea.
“华盛顿广场公园捎来的问候”
史蒂芬妮上哪间大学？
Where did Stephanie go to college？
我们来这里又是干嘛？
Why are we here again？
明信片上的号码
Those numbers on Stephanie Chan's postcard
其实是书籍的索书号
are actually a call number for a book.
索书号开头是字母
Call numbers start with letters.
在国会图书馆是没错
In the Library of Congress, yeah.
在哈佛燕京图书馆属亚洲文学类
In Harvard-Yenching, it's a classification for Asian literature.
你怎么会知道这种事？
How could you possibly know that？
几年前 我就在 武汉
你会说中文？
You speak Chinese？
不可思议
Unbelievable.
汉克麦斯崔诺两周前死于车祸
Hank Maestriano died two weeks ago. Car crash.
丹尼尔麦金提
Daniel McGinty.
上周死于心脏病发作
Heart attack. Last week.
但如果这是暗杀名单
But, if this is a hit list,
为什么这个人仍活着？
why is this guy still alive？
盖布欧辛格
Gabriel Singer.
他开货机
Flies cargo planes.
这是个好问题
That's a good question.
真棘手
Hell of a mess.
快接
Come on.
请接乔麦特森
Joe Matheson, please.
稍候
Hold on.
玛娜
Marna.
喂？
Hello？
怎样？
What？
乔
Joe.
中情局总部,维吉尼亚州兰利
法兰克莫西斯不是…
Frank Moses is not a retired analyst
从无实战经验的退休分析员
who's never worked in the field.
这家伙的经历不简单
This guy has a history.
这是档案号码
That's a file number.
你需要去密室
You need to visit the back room.
去找纪录保管员
You're going to meet the Records Keeper.
我根本不知道有这种地方存在
I didn't even know this place existed.
是不存在
It doesn't.
法兰克莫西斯的档案
Ah. Uh. Frank Moses' file.
搞什么鬼
You gotta be kidding me.
法兰克莫西斯是…
Frank Moses was one of the most effective black op agents
本局最优秀的秘密行动探员之一
we've ever had.
他暗杀毒枭和恐怖份子
He retired drug-lords, terrorists,
要命,他还推翻过政府
hell, he toppled governments.
没错,他确实有天赋
Yeah. He was truly gifted.
他为什么退休？
Why was he retired？
老了
He got old.
然后一些菜鸟报到
Then some thumb sucker
给他取了昵称“RED”
came along and tagged him “RED”.
“RED”？
Red？
RED,退休的超危险特工
Yeah, RED, you know, R. E. D. “Retired: Extremely Dangerous”.
好
Yeah.
现在的新人都比他逊多了
Yeah. They don't make 'em like that anymore.
谢了
Thanks.
我需要收集完整资料
I'm gonna need a data haunt.
他监督过的每个探员
Every flap he was ever involved in. Every agent he's ever run.
我要国家安全局的电话监控 语音识别
I want NSA telephone surveillance, voice recognition…
彭萨科拉,佛罗里达州
我们必须找到马文巴格斯
We have to find Marvin Boggs.
马文两年前死于火灾
Marvin died two years ago in a fire.
是啊,马文死了几百次
Yeah. Marvin has died many times.
能搭那玩意吗？
Oh, can we have that one？
再来个五弦琴更有范儿
Wow. All we need is a banjo. Ssh！ Ssh！ Ssh！
小声点
Keep your voice down.
别贸然行动
Don ' t make any sudden moves.
跟紧我,别用手机
Just stay close to me. Don't use your cell phone.
你拿走我的手机
Uh, you took my cell phone.
别提到手机,别提到卫星
Don't talk about cell phones. Don ' t talk about satellites.
当真？
Seriously？
你为什么想杀我？
Why are you trying to kill me？
我哪有想杀你
I'm not trying to kill you！
你就是有
Oh, yeah. You are.
我干嘛要杀你？
Why would I be trying to kill you？
因为上次见面时,我想杀你
Because the last time we met, I tried to kill you.
那是陈年往事了
That was a long time ago.
有些人就是爱记恨啊
Some people hold on to things like that.
我不想杀你
I'm not trying to kill you.
好吗？
Okay？
所以我们是同一阵线,对吧？
So that makes us friends. Right？
对
Right.
很好
Good.
能把刀移开我的蛋蛋了吗？
Wanna take that knife out of my balls now？
她是谁？
Who is she？
莎拉,她也不想杀你
Sarah. She's not trying to kill you either.
对,嗨
Yeah. Hi.
我不能呆在外面
I don't stay in the open.
来吧,我带你们去我家
Come on, I'll show you the house.
那是什么？
What's that？
幌子
Decoy.
他住在车里？
He lives in a car？
进来吧
Come on in.
你何必住这里？你明明有房子
Why do you live here？ When you have the other place.
我这样解释好了
Let's, uh, put it this way.
去年直升机飞过我家
When the helicopter passed over the house last year,
我感觉他们盯上我
and I could feel their eyes on me.
充满杀气
Wet like, like peaches.
我这里有份名单
I have a list here.
由一名遇害记者所写
It was written by a reporter who's now dead.
名单上的每个人也被杀害
Along with everyone whose names are on that list.
几乎每个人
Well, almost everyone.
法兰克,我跟你说过几遍？
Frank, Frank, how many times have I told you？
不能信任体制
You cannot trust the system！
当你身在体制之中
I told you, when you're in the system,
弹指间就会被干掉
they switch the flip and you're done.
卫星、手机
Man, satellites,
晶片、网络、网路、牙医…
cell phones, chips, net, the web, the dentist-
马文！
Marvin！
我们需要借助于这份名单
That list is the one we need help with.
好,我得检查档案
Yeah, I gotta check the files.
当然,谢了
Of course you do. Thanks, man.
这家伙疯了
This guy's insane.
他自以为是…
Well, he thought he was the subject
秘密政府心智控制计划的对象
of a secret government mind control project.
需要一些时间
This'll take a minute.
是咧
Sure.
结果…
As it turns out,
他的确11年来每天都嗑点迷幻药
he really was being given daily doses of LSD for eleven years.
那样看来,他很正常
Well, in that case, he looks great.
正常毙了
Fantastic. Yeah.
找到了,瓜地马拉,1981年秋天
Got it. Guatemala. Fall, nineteen eighty-one.
除了我们,名单上的五人在那里
Five of the guys on this list were there, not including us.
就在圣班尼托外围
Uh, San Benito, uh, just outside.
印第安人领地
Injun territory.
有个小村落,村民被杀光
Yeah. Was a little village. Uh, everybody was killed. Civilians, everybody.
上级要我们“去那里湮灭证据”
They told us “Go in there. Clean it up.
“让这事件看似从未发生”
Make it look like it never happened.”
你认为名单上的每个人都在场？
You, you think everyone on this list was there？
该死
Dammit.
Dammit！
知道这国家的问题何在？
Do you know what's wrong with this country？
大家都想杀我们？
They're all trying to kill us？
没错！
Exactly！
名单上还有人幸存吗？
Is there anybody still alive on that list？
盖布欧辛格
Gabriel Singer.
法兰克
Frank！
我从没料到我会再撂这句话
I never thought I'd say this again.
我要亮出猪公了！
I am gettin' the pig！
她在跟谁说话？
Who's she talking to？
别紧张
Just take it easy.
法兰克,我们要解决这女人
Frank, we gotta get rid of this broad.
我知道附近有个理想弃尸地
I know a great place, just up the road.
有许多鳄鱼
Lotsa alligators.
我们不解决这女人
We're not gettin' rid of the broad.
我喜欢她,好吗？
I like her. Okay？
什么动机？
Well, wait, what's the angle？
没有动机,就是喜欢
No angle. I like her.
他们可能正从付费电话…
Okay. So, they pull her voice from the pay phone,
追踪到她的声音
probably right now,
再装设辨识软件回溯到辛格
install the recognition software and back-trace it to Singer.
然后我们现身时
So then we show up,
他们会部署卫星
they bring out the satellite,
我们就会在Y射线下嗝屁
and we're fried with Y-rays. Mmm.
你没病吧？
How you doing？
放心啦
Good, fine.
N9745
November niner seven four five…
辛格明天会去莫比尔
Wow. Singer is going to be in Mobile tomorrow.
我们能在飞机航站跟他碰面
We can catch him at the airfreight terminal.
这样好吗？
How about that？
莫比尔,阿拉巴马州
日落公司开往纽奥良…
The Sunset Limited with service to New Orleans,
休士顿、土桑和洛杉矶的巴士
Houston, Tucson and Los Angeles
正在第五月台搭车
now boarding platform five.
这是东向快车的最后搭车通知
It's the final boarding call for the eastbound Express.
不要,拜托！不要…！
Oh, my G-！ Oh, no, please！ Oh, no, please！ Please, no！
你感觉像华盛顿人
You smell like Washington.
你替谁工作？
- Oh！ - Who do you work for？
科威不动产,我是房产经纪人
Coldwell Banker, I'm a real estate agent！ -Just take my money, - No. No no.
拜托,别伤害我
- please, please, don't hurt me.
不,你替谁工作？
- No no. Who do you work for？
什么？
What？
-你替谁工作？ -马文！住手！
- Who do you work for？ - Marvin！
她跟他们一伙,她一直跟踪我们
- Whoa！ Wait a minute！ - Frank, she's one of them. She's been following us.
她袋子里有摄影机
There's a camera in her bag.
我要立刻杀了她
- I'm gonna kill her now. - Wait！ Wait just- Marvin！
不,拜托别杀我
No, no, please don't kill-
别让他杀我
Don't let him kill me, please.
马文,等等,别冲动
Marvin, just wait, would you, please？
马文,你看,马文
Marvin. Look. Marvin.
袋子里没摄影机
No camera in the bag.
快走,女士,赶快
Go, ma'am, now. Now.
去租车
Get a car.
尽量别杀人
Try not to kill anyone.
她跟踪我们
She was following us, Frank.
抱歉
Sorry.
“她袋子里有摄影机”
“She has a camera in her purse,
“我们必须杀她？”
we have to kill her”？
没搞错吧？
Seriously？
待会见
See you in a minute.
盖布欧？
Gabriel？
对吧？盖布欧辛格？
Right？ Gabriel Singer？
怎么回事？
What's this about？
瓜地马拉,1981年秋天
Guatemala. Nineteen eighty-one.
圣班尼托
San Benito.
我不便谈话
I can't talk to you.
寡不敌众
Pair beats ace.
给你们猜个谜语
I got one for you.
一名两度受勋的…
What did this twice-decorated,
西德州犹太海军飞行员…
west Texas Jew-boy Marine pilot say
对纽约时报中国记者说了什么？
to the Chinese New York Times reporter？
我放弃
I give up.
啥都没有,我啥都没告诉她
Nothing. I didn't tell her a damn thing.
这名记者现在死了
The reporter's dead now.
她谈过话的每个人
And everyone she spoke to is either dead or a target.
不是死就是成为目标,包括你
And that includes you.
老天
Oh, Christ.
上级要我在黑夜中载个人去那里
They had me fly this guy out there in the dead of night.
令人发毛的鸟不生蛋小机场
Hairy little airstrip in the middle of nowhere.
他是中情局探员
He was CIA,
穿西装打领带的肉脚间谍
some dorky little spook in a suit and tie.
记得下命令的人吗？
Remember that guy？
黑框眼镜
Black glasses… Yeah, he was giving the orders.
他拿着一个包裹,我载他飞离当地
He picked up a package and I flew him back out.
什么包裹？
What was the package？
不是装东西
It wasn't a what.
是装人
It was a who.
法兰克,法兰克…！
Frank. Frank, Frank！
是那台直升机
It's that helicopter.
既然我们在机场…
W-we're in an airport. So…
是同一台直升机
It's the same helicopter.
N9748C
November niner seven four eight Charlie.
看吧,N9748…
See？ Frank, it- November niner seven four eight-
那是4吗？
Is that a four？
是4C
This is a four. Charlie.
那是7吗？那是什么？
Is that a seven？
我告诉你们那是什么
- What is that one right there？ - I'll tell you what it is. It's a four.
我早说她不该打那通电话！
I told you she shouldn't've made that phone call！
我们看不到目标了
We lost visual on target.
好,轰出他们
Alright. Shake the tree.
你会付损害赔偿？
You'll pay for the breakage？
对,确认
Yeah, Roger that.
没错,欧吉桑！
That's right, old man！
欧吉桑？
Old man？
没礼貌
No respect.
现在能杀她了？
Can I kill her now？
她叫我欧吉桑
She called me an old man.
猪公！打开猪公！
Pig！ Open the pig！
好
Okay.
手榴弹！
Grenade！
该死的卫星
Damn satellites！
去死吧
Boop to that！
很好,乖乖待着
Yeah, you just stay right there.
好戏登场了
This is gonna be good.
你没事吧？
You okay？
没事
Yeah.
起来,没事吧？
Come on, come on. Hey. Alright？
你要干嘛？
What are you doin'？
欧你老母
Old man, my ass.
混帐东西
God damn it！
烟雾和热气,遮住视线
Smoke and thermals. Obstructed view.
讯号减弱
Signal's fading.
好枪法
Nice shot.
谢了
Thanks.
该闪人了
We should get out of here.
你真会逗女生开心,法兰克
You really know how to show a girl a good time, Frank.
我会宰了你,马文
I will kill you, Marvin.
别激动,她喜欢你
Take it easy, man. She likes you.
你怎么知道？
How can you tell？
有注意到她黏着你不放？
Hmm. Notice how she sticks around？
女人不哈你才不会跟你勾勾缠
'Cause if women don't like you, they don't stick around.
她有别的选择吗？
She doesn't have much of a choice. Does she？
她当然有
Sure she does.
真的？
Really？
你觉得？
You think so？
如果对方是中情局
You know, if it is the CIA.
那我们只能去一个地方…
Then there's only one place that we can go to find out
查明他们为什么追杀我们
why they're coming after us.
没错
Yeah.
我们在那里八成会被干掉
We're gonna get killed there, for sure.
拼了或落跑？
In or out？
当然是拼了,我只是说说
No, of course I'm in. I'm just…saying.
我们需要强大帮手
We're gonna need some serious help.
“俄罗斯大使馆”
我指的不是这种帮手
Th-This is not the kind of help I meant, Frank.
你不是当真要进去吧？
You're not actually gonna go, go in there, are you？
我会很害怕,法兰克
I don't think I can go, Frank.
上次他们电击我的…
The, the last time they put some electrical wires
某些宝贝部位
in some not very nice places.
听着,替我保管
Listen, hang onto that for me.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
小心
Hey. Be careful.
跟伊凡西蒙诺夫说法兰克莫西斯…
Tell Ivan Simonov that Frank Moses is-
法兰克莫西斯来这里见他
Frank Moses is- Frank Moses- Frank Moses is here to see him.
我得承认
I have to say,
这是我今早起床时
this is the last thing I expected
打死也想不到的事
when I got up this morning.
我好几次梦到我杀了你
I have many times dreamed of killing you.
但如今
But now,
你是…
you are a…
靠养老金过活
pensioner.
好几年了
Couple of years now.
时间飞逝
Time passes.
随着我们变老
As we get older,
一切变得微不足道
things seem less important.
然而…
Still,
我应该报复你…
I owe you for
杀了伊果
killing Igor.
屠夫伊果
Igor the Butcher.
他是重大资产
He was a great asset.
他是猪头
He was a pig.
他是我表亲
He was my cousin.
很遗憾
I ' m sorry.
敬伊果
To Igor.
屠夫
The Butcher.
他没死
He's not dead.
我唆使他投诚
I flipped him.
少来
No.
他在橘郡拥有好几间7-11便利店
He owns a string of Seven-Elevens in Orange County.
胖到2百多公斤
He weighs five hundred pounds.
喝
Drink.
这次敬谁？
Who are we drinking to, now？
薇若妮卡
Veronique.
她向我投诚
She was mine.
不可能
Impossible.
是的
Yes！
给她多少好处都值得
Whatever she got, it was worth it.
我怀念往日
I miss the old days.
我好几年没杀人了
I haven't killed anyone in years.
太可悲了
That's sad.
不过…
But
我想你来这里不是想喝伏特加
I think you are not here for the vodka.
我要闯入中情局
I'm going to break into the CIA.
我需要你的完整保全布局蓝图
I need your complete security layout of Langley.
破解法、密码、识别证
Cracks. Codes. ID swipes.
一切所需
All of it.
这种天大的乐事…
Amusing as this would be,
已超出我的能力范围
it is beyond my reach.
法兰克莫西斯想利益交换？
A favor from Frank Moses？
兰利,维吉尼亚州
没想到你竟然让我跟来
I can't believe you're actually letting me come along.
伊凡给我们的识别证是哈洛将军
The badges Ivan gave us are for a General Harlow
以及洛杉矶的女核物理学家
and a female nuclear physicist from Los Alamos.
珊妮奎强生？
Sheniqua Johnson？
你被领养
You're adopted.
好
Okay.
太酷了
This is so cool.
“准备视网膜扫瞄”
怎样？
What？
我弄丢了
Oh！ I, I, I, I dropped it. Um, I'll find it.
“扫瞄完成”
别动！
Freeze！
将军弄丢隐型眼镜
The General has dropped his contact lens.
或许你们能帮我们？
Perhaps you'd like to help us？
对不起
Sorry.
找到了！我找到了！
Found it！ I found it！
我找到了
I found it.
“通过监定”
今天愉快,将军
Have a good day, sir.
各位
Gentlemen.
我的天啊
My God！
我们在这里的行为会判什么罪？
What do you suppose the, the punishment is for what we're doing here？
死刑
Death.
或许无期徒刑
Maybe life in prison.
太屌了
Awesome.
你干嘛按着那个键？
Why are you holding that button？
俄国人有给你密码吗？
The Russians give you the code？
没有
No.
每6小时变更一次
Changes every six hours.
替我拿一下好吗？
Will you hold that for me for a second？
好
Yeah.
无法解码
It's unbreakable.
天啊
Wow.
来吧
Come on.
莫西斯先生
Mister Moses！
好久不见
Been a long time.
我需要看瓜地马拉档案
I'm gonna need to see that Guatemala file.
瓜地马拉？
Guatemala？
对
Yes.
我想我能帮你
Uh huh. I think I can help you.
太好了
Great.
你离开后这里彻底改观
You know, it's been a whole new world around here since you left.
瓜地马拉
Guatemala.
你帮我会被骂臭头
You know, you're gonna catch hell for this.
鸟事我遇多了
After what I've seen？
我该告知你
Oh-oh, I should tell you,
昨天有个新人来这里找你的档案
there's a new guy came down here yesterday looking for your file.
名字是威廉库伯？
Name of, uh, William Cooper？
185公分？娘炮发型？
Six-one？ Cute hair？
是很娘
Mm, it was cute.
但他看起来倒像个狠角色
But I thought he looked a little tough, though.
好好保重,亨利
You take good care of yourself, Henry.
你也是,莫西斯先生
You, too, Mister Moses.
计划改变
Change of plan.
惹错人了,欧吉桑
Bad move, Grandpa.
跟他的档案照差很大
Just looks completely different than his profile pictures. So…
柯戴斯基训练你的？
Kordesky trained you？
对
Yeah.
柯戴斯基是我徒弟
I trained Kordesky.
王八蛋！
Son of a bitch！
封锁大楼,秃头白人、五十几岁
Seal the building. Bald, white male, fifties,
穿白衬衫蓝裤子,肩膀中枪
wearing white shirt, blue pants, shot in the shoulder.
嗨
Hi.
该闪人了,快闪人
We should go. We should go now.
每个出口都设检查站,火警呢？
I've got checkpoints at every exit. What about the fire？
关闭警报器,我说过没火灾
Shut off the alarm. I told you, there is no fire！
我们需要撤离
We need to evacuate.
不,这只是声东击西
No, this is just a diversion.
确定每个人都经检查
You make sure everyone gets checked.
救命,救命！拜托过来！
Help！ Help, help！
我无法止血
Please come！ I can't stop the bleeding.
先生,你没事吧？
You okay, sir？
让出通道！
Make a hole！
等等,让我看他
Whoa, whoa, hold it, hold it.
不是他
Let me see him. It's not him.
快走
Yeah, yeah, go ahead.
各位,这里需要帮忙
Fellas, help me out, here.
马文？
Marvin？
这家伙的脑袋还是不对劲
There's still something wrong with this guy's head, Frank.
你不是盖的,乔
You're really something, Joe.
马文,你没事吧？
Marvin, you okay？
我不想讨论
I don't want to talk about it.
乔？挂掉的那个乔？
Joe？ Joe？ Joe who was dead Joe？
她跟我们同伙？
She with us？
对
Yeah.
还没挂
Not dead.
只是退休
Just retired.
你杀过来省了热线
I guess calling wasn't an option？
能走了吗？
Can we go？
好
Yeah！
你让自己中弹？
You let yourself get shot？
见鬼了
God damn it.
出去
Out.
你没事吧？
You okay？
谢了,医生
Thanks, Doc.
他偷了什么？
What did he get？
我不知道
I have no idea.
你竟然白白被退休老将海扁一顿
You just had your ass handed to you by a goddamn retiree.
他干了什么？
What did he do？
莫西斯干了什么导致被下灭口令？
What did Moses do to earn a lethal finding？
上级没有告知
I have not been read into it.
我欣赏你,库伯
I like you, Cooper.
你有野心又有战绩
You're ambitious and you get results,
但有人闯入我们地盘撒野
but someone just kicked in the front door of our house,
你最好能搞定这件鸟事
so you better get your shit straight.
你的任务维持不变
Nothing in your mission is changed.
你还在流血
You're still bleedin'. Mm hmm.
子弹一定射中了要害
Must have nicked something in there.
情况真糟
This is so bad.
没那么糟,中弹是家常便饭
It's not that bad. People get shot all the time.
才不是,一般人顶多被纸割
No, they don't, they get paper cuts.
我大多是中弹
I mostly get shot.
我们得找人替他止血
Well, we're gonna have to find somebody to plug this leak.
可以去鹰巢
Could go to Eagle's Nest.
那我们全都会中弹
Then we all get shot.
我单独进去
I'll just go in by myself.
要防弹背心吗？
Want a vest？
没鸟用
Wouldn't do any good.
鹰巢,马里兰州切萨皮克
法兰克莫西斯
Frank Moses.
嗨,维多莉亚
Hi, Victoria.
你来这里杀我吗？
Are you here to kill me？
不是
No.
你中弹了
You've been shot.
叫马文别轻举妄动,否则会挂彩
Tell Marvin to stand down before he gets hurt.
那女孩是谁？
Who's the girl？
她跟我一道
She's with me.
维姬
Vicky. Joe！
乔
Oh, Vicky.
维姬,老了还是一样火辣辣
Sexy as ever. Oh.
你这老万人迷
Oh, you old snake charmer, you.
莎拉,这位是维多莉亚
Sarah, this is Victoria.
业界最优刺客
Best wet work asset in the business.
也是一流的狙击高手
And a true artist with an RPN.
那是什么东东？
What's- what's that？
我杀人为业,小妞
I kill people, dear.
你运气好
You were lucky.
你怎么做到的？
How'd you do it？
什么？
What？
你怎么调适退休生活？
How'd you make the transition？
你似乎很平静、很自在
Here you seem so calm. At ease.
我喜欢
I love it. I love it here.
我喜欢这里
I love the baking.
喜欢烘焙、喜欢插花
I love the flower arranging.
我喜欢日常生活
I like, I like the routine.
不过…有时我会手痒
Well, I, I do get a bit restless sometimes.
我会打零工重操旧业
I take the odd contract on the side.
过过杀人瘾
I, I just can't stop.
说来听听
Yeah. Tell me about it.
人不可能说变就变
You can't just flip a switch and become someone else.
用力压住
Put some pressure on it.
那么…
So…
谈谈你的女性友人
tell me about your lady friend.
她让我觉得我能确实…
Makes me think that I could actually…
拥有人生
have a life.
真正的人生
A real life.
法兰克,你真是浪漫胚子
Oh, Francis, you're such a romantic.
什么？
What？
浪漫胚子,难怪我一直很在意你
A romantic. It ' s why I've always been so fond of you.
维多莉亚
Victoria…
你外表很强悍,不过你…
You're all hard on the outside, but you are…
你内心很感性
you are gooey on the inside.
感性
Gooey.
瓜地马拉档案的整个后半部
The entire back half of the Guatemala
都被涂黑
file has been blacked out.
不过有份名单,11个名字
But there's a list. Eleven names.
加上一人被删去
Plus one that's been redacted.
全死光,除了法兰克和马文
All dead. Except for Frank and Marvin.
记者名单的所有名字也在档案中
All the names on the reporter's list are in the file, too,
但她多出一个名字
but she has an additional name.
亚历山大丹宁,有人在保护他
Alexander Dunning. Somebody's protecting him.
丹宁是布朗宁奥维斯的执行长
Dunning is the CEO of Browning-Orvis.
不法份子
Gangsters.
国防部契约商,后台很硬
Defense contractor. Very connected.
如果中情局在保护他
You know, if the CIA is protecting him,
他就在监控下
he's under surveillance.
我们能去见他
We could go see him.
你们少不了我
You're not going without me.
好耶
Well,
我们归队重出江湖,帅喔
we're getting the band back together. That's nice.
喂？
Yeah？
获悉情报,超危险特工有新目标
We just got a tip. Red has a new target.
情报？
A tip？
联邦调查局在现场
FBI's on the scene.
我这就过去
I'm on my way.
调查局在东侧周边设立看守位置
The FBI has a lookout position on the east perimeter.
收到
Copy that.
亚历山大丹宁
Alexander Dunning.
幸会,巴提斯部长
Pleasure to see you, Secretary Baptiste.
我很荣幸
The pleasure is with me.
他们进入了
They're in.
法兰克说你要我跟着你
Frank said you wanted me with you.
对,我想来点姊妹淘时间不赖
Yes, I thought it might be nice to have a bit of girl time together.
彼此了解
You know, get to know each other？
我只想告诉你
And I, I, I just wanted to tell you
我认识法兰克这么多年
that in all the years I've known Francis,
我从没看他为爱所苦
I've never seen him like this.
所以如果你害他心碎
So if you break his heart,
我会杀了你
I will kill you.
再把你的尸体埋在树林中
And bury your body in the woods.
阿娘喂
Wow.
好
Okay.
这一定会很好玩
Ah, this is gonna be fun.
在布朗宁奥维斯
Here at Browning-Orvis…
我们长年致力于人道事业
we have a longstanding commitment to humanitarian causes,
因为模范的企业公民是…
because exemplary corporate citizenship
我们的最高天职
is our highest calling.
身为一间拥有…
As a company with global
全球版图和全球营运的公司
reach and global interests,
我们负有全球责任
we have global responsibilities.
有时我会被问
Now sometimes I'm asked if this commitment
这种道德行为的贡献…
to ethical behavior
是否影响公司宗旨
affects the bottom line.
我的答案永远一致
And my answer is always the same.
是的
Yes.
能使公司更壮大
It makes it stronger.
这是我的安全房
This is my safe room. Sound-proofed.
隔音、强化,每天扫查监听装置
Mmm. Reinforced. Swept for bugs daily.
就算在这里开枪
You could fire a gun in here.
也没人会知道
No one would ever know.
丹宁先生
Mister Dunning,
我无法想像更适合谈生意的场所
I cannot imagine a more perfect place to conduct our business.
你想必明白会有…
You do know that there's a,
额外费用
uh, surcharge
对于运送任何武器到…
for any arms deliveries to countries
联合国禁运的国家
that are embargoed by the United Nations.
先生,针对任何问题
For every problem, monsieur,
都有解决方法
there is a solution.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
什么…？
What are y-？
有多少执行长能这样说？
How many CEOs can say that？
你们怎么认识的？
So how did you guys meet？
我们一开始是讲电话
We started talking on the phone.
我想我喜欢这种不真实感
I guess I liked that it wasn't real.
如今我在逃亡,中情局要杀我
Course now I'm a fugitive,
我要躲避藏身
the CIA wants to kill me and I'm hiding in a hole.
我曾爱上一名特务
You know, I was in love with an agent once.
发生什么事？
What happened？
我隶属英国情报局
Well, I was with MI6.
这段关系未获…
And the relationship wasn't…
“批准”
“sanctioned.”
因此曝光时,我的忠诚度被质疑
So when it came to light, my loyalty was questioned,
我受命暗杀他
and I was ordered to kill him.
是个测试
It was a test.
你怎么做？
What did you do？
我朝他胸口开了三枪
I put three bullets in his chest.
好
Okay.
你们到底是何方神圣？
Who the hell are you guys？
你不记得我们了？
You don't remember us？
我们记得你
We remember you.
我们在1981年瓜地马拉行动
You're the guy whose shit we cleaned up down in Guatemala
替你收烂摊子
in nineteen eighty-one.
问题在于,你载谁飞离那里？
And the question is, who did you fly out of there？
你们不懂自己卷入什么麻烦
You don't have any idea what you're getting into.
首先,你们不能动我
First of all, you can't touch me.
骗谁
Sure, we can.
好耶
Oh, yeah.
你这哪里来的？
Where'd you get this？
特力屋
Home Depot.
多少钱？
How much？
10元
Ten bucks.
想试蛋蛋吗？
You want nuts,
乳头？
nipples,
捅菊花？
potty trainer？
好,够了
Alright, stop it.
蛋蛋
Nuts.
住手,帮帮忙！住手！
Stop it.
给我住手！
For the love of Christ, stop it！ Stop already！
现在你有话要说了？
Now you got something to say？
我们送走一名年轻中尉
We extracted a young lieutenant
他是已故参议员…
who is the son of
詹姆斯史坦登的儿子
the late Senator James Stanton.
罗勃史坦登？
Robert Stanton？
美国副总统
Vice President of the United States.
你是说副总统杀光整个村？
You're saying the Vice President killed all the people in that village？
对,他抓狂了
Yeah. Went completely off the reservation.
那名纽约时报记者呢？
And that New York Times reporter？
她有逼问你吗？
Did she pressure you？
有,她打给我,两次
Yeah. Yeah. She called me.
于是我打给副总统
Twice. So I called the V.P.
那你认为会发生什么事？
And, uh, what did you think would happen then？
管它的
Oh, whatever.
我将他拱上副总统
I made him Vice President.
你封口,史坦登家族使你有钱
You kept your mouth shut and the Stantons made you rich.
在开发中世界跟我们伙伴携手
Been working with our partners in the developing world
根除腐败…
to root out corruption an- - corruption an- - corruption an-- corruption an--
好
Okay.
价钱随你们开
I will pay whatever it
只要了结这件事
costs to get rid of this thing…
我们来这里不是向你讨钱,老友
We're not here for your money, home.
我们来这里是因为…
We're here because that
纽约时报记者有那份名单
New York Times reporter had the list of names.
记载瓜地马拉行动的每个人
Knew everybody who was in Guatemala.
名单上的每个人都被下令杀害
And everybody on that list has been ordered killed.
除了你
Except you.
这跟我无关
I had nothing to do with that.
你们不懂吗？
Don ' t you see？
他想清除不光彩过去
He's trying to clean up his past
一枪毙了我
and get rid of me in one shot.
他想在选总统之前跟我划清界线
He's trying to cut me loose before he runs for President.
外头这里有重大活动
We have some major activity out here.
看来我们走漏风声
Looks like we're blown.
就定位,周边防线建立,无人可逃
We're in position. Perimeter's set. No one's getting out.
他们在东侧部署队伍
They're moving a team up the east side.
要让我跟他们谈吗？
Are you gonna let me talk to them？
我能交涉出结果
I can negotiate something.
谢了,要你帮忙还不如吃狗屎
Thanks, when we want your help, we'll get out the drain cleaner.
听着,塑胶男
Listen, Plastic Man,
外头那些家伙可能也受命要杀我
those bastards out there probably have orders to kill me, too.
希望如此
I hope so.
为什么？因为我是坏蛋？
Why？ 'Cause I'm a “bad guy”？
我是人渣？
I'm scum？
我能现在就毙了他吗？
Can I just shoot him now？
不行
No.
不能乱杀人
You don't have people killed.
我乱杀人,我是坏蛋,记得吧？
I have people killed, I'm the bad guy. Remember？
别浪费子弹
Not worth a bullet.
喂？
Hello？
法兰克,退休好吗？
How's retirement, Frank？
爽到爆
It's been a real blast.
我们进去抓你就场面难看了
If we have to come in there and get you, it's gonna be messy.
好说,难看毙了
You bet. Real messy.
我听命行事,法兰克
I've got my orders, Frank.
副总统的命令
They come from the Vice President.
他下令暗杀行动
He's ordered these hits to cover up the war crimes
掩盖他在瓜地马拉犯下的战争罪
he committed in Guatemala.
鬼才相信
Well, I find that hard to believe.
你怎么知道来这里找我？
How did you know you'd find me here？
匿名的不明情报？
Some anonymous untraceable tip？
谈个交易,法兰克
Here's the deal, Frank.
你从前门出来投降
You're gonna walk out that /front door and give yourself up.
我向你保证没人会开枪
You have my word no one will shoot you.
我会亲自护送你投案
I will personally take you in,
让你发表个人说法
and you will get to tell your side of the story.
你有60秒时间决定
You got sixty seconds to decide.
局势如何？
What's it look like？
没有逃生出口
There's no clean exit.
他们似乎全面封锁
They seem to be coming from everywhere.
只要能转移注意力
If we had a distraction,
我能掩护你们到树林
I could cover you to the woods.
看来别无选择了,小子
Looks like there's not a lot of options, kid.
也就是…
I mean…
如果我们要活着离开
somebody's gonna have to make the hard choice
有人就得做出牺牲决定
if we're gonna get out of here alive.
太热血了
Been wild.
热血又疯狂
Wild and crazy.
不过我死而无憾
But I wouldn ' t want it any other way.
向你致敬
An honor.
祝好运
Good luck.
叫你的人停火
Tell your men to hold their fire.
我要出来了
I'm comin' out.
他要出来了,所有单位停火
He's coming out. All units, hold fire.
重复,所有单位停火
Repeat, all units, hold fire.
确认
Roger that.
躲在我后面
Get behind.
赶快出来,我掩护你们
Come out now. I've got you covered.
是谁开枪？
Who fired the shot？
他们找到掩护时告诉我
Tell me when the boys make cover,
我们要撤退
we'll move.
现在
Now.
他们捉到莎拉了
They've got Sarah.
你送死也救不回她
Frank, you're no good to her dead.
我们得走人了
We gotta move.
快点,没时间磨蹭了
Come！ Now is not time to waste.
伊凡？
Ivan？
很高兴再遇到你,伊凡
It's nice to see you again, Ivan.
他刚叫你“小兔子”？
Did he just call you “bunny”？
人生有时很复杂
Life sometimes is complicated.
敬乔
To Joe.
乔
Joe. Joe.
我不想越界参一脚
Not to push the bounds of propriety…
不过你们不觉得该探讨为何…
but don't you think we ought to discuss the fact that
副总统利用中情局作为个人暗杀团
the CIA's being used by the Vice President as his personal hit squad and that they'll do whatever
以及为何他们不择手段追杀我们？
they can to find us and kill us？
建议采取什么行动？
Options？
我们能公开真相
We could go public.
是咧,那名记者就因此丧命
Yeah, right. That didn't work very well for the reporter.
那法兰克的女友呢？
And what about Frank's girlfriend？
他们很快会杀掉她
They'll kill her so fast.
首先会拷问她
I mean, first they'll interrogate her.
他们可能已经用过电击
They probably already got the wires.
然后来点水刑,再加上电击
Then give her a little snorkel. Give her a jump. Bring in the dent-
-接着拔牙… -马文！
Marvin！
天！你真是个白痴
God！ You are such an idiot.
我要给你看样东西
I want to show you something.
这是我人生最爱留下的印记
This was done to me by the love of my life.
似乎我们的爱是禁忌
It seems that what we had was not meant to be.
但如今她坐在…
But now she sits outside
我家外头
my house
喝着伏特加
drinking vodka.
胸口三枪
Three bullets in the chest.
我活着醒来时
When I woke alive,
我就明白她仍爱着我
I knew she still loved me.
不然我会头部开花毙命
Or else it would have been the head.
当然她冒着很大风险
It was big risk for her, of course,
不过人们会为爱做出疯狂事
but one does crazy things for love.
别为你的爱人恐惧,朋友
Do not fear for your love, my friend.
借助于一小群忠诚伙伴
With a small dedicated group,
凡事都能迎刃而解
there is nothing that cannot be accomplished.
我直话直说
Let me be blunt.
没人知道你在这里,你不存在
Nobody knows you're here. You don't exist.
除非你充分合作
And unless you cooperate fully,
否则我会毫不吝啬使出任何手段
there's nothing I can't do to you.
先生
Sir…
现在不方便
Not now.
莫西斯在线上
Moses is on the phone.
启动追踪
Okay, trace is running.
莫西斯
Moses.
听好了,库伯
Here's the thing, Cooper.
不经一事,不长一智
With age comes a certain perspective.
如果我不承认有过你这种时期
I'd be a liar if I said there wasn't a time
我就是说谎
when I was exactly like you.
盲目的野心
Blind ambition.
错置的信任
Misplaced trust.
你为什么告诉我这些？
Why are you telling me this？
这可能会帮助我决定下一步
It might help me to decide what to do next.
继续谈话
Almost there, almost there, just keep it going, keep it going.
为什么？你在想什么？
Why？ What are you thinking about？
我们这一行很艰难
Our business is a very hard one.
不过困扰我的绝非…
But it was never the,
杀人或压力
the killing or the stress,
或薪水少得可怜
or the bad pay that bothered me.
法兰克,那么是什么？
Well, what was it, Frank？
是你所爱的一切
It's how anything that you love
会被夺走
can be taken away from you.
这教导我绝不爱人
It taught me never to care.
绝不动情
Never to invest.
然后我遇到这女人
Then I met this woman,
莎拉
Sarah.
现在她在你手里
And now you have her.
如今我想不到更恐怖的事…
Now I can't think of anything more horrible than to know that
比起知道敌人能伤害你所爱之人
your enemies can hurt someone that you love.
这种感觉几乎不可名状
The feeling is almost indescribable.
库伯,你还在吗？
You still there, Cooper？
你在我家
You're at my house.
几乎不可名状,对吧？
Almost indescribable, isn't it？
拜托
Please. Please,
拜托别伤害我家人
don't hurt my family.
要是莎拉发生任何事
If anything happens to Sarah,
我会毁了你人生所爱的一切
I will rip everything you love out of your life.
然后我会杀了你
And then I'll kill you.
我向你保证会使莎拉安全
I swear to you, I will keep Sarah safe.
时间不多了,你了解吗？
We don't have much time. Do you understand that？
法兰克,你打算怎么做？
What are you gonna do, Frank？
我要杀了副总统
I'm gonna kill the Vice President.
你打算怎么做？
What are you gonna do？
快点！
Move！ Move！
妈！
Mom！
法兰克留下这个给我
Frank left this for me.
他哪里拿到的？
Where did he get it from？
中情局的机密纪录库
The secure records depository of the CIA.
听着,莎拉
Look, Sarah.
我知道法兰克说对一些事
I know Frank's been right about a few things.
不过他即将越过无法回头的界线
But he's about to cross a line from which there's no turning back.
现在你有机会帮助他
Right now, you have an opportunity to help him.
你需要告诉我你所知的一切
You need to tell me everything you know.
因为如果我不能阻止他
Because if I can't stop him…
我就必须杀他
I'm gonna have to kill him.
你知道法兰克莫西斯的真面目？
Do you know who Frank Moses is？ I mean, really is？
你知道他做过什么？
Do you know what, what he's done？
天啊
Wow.
你要求我帮忙？有够孬的
You're asking me for help？ That is so lame.
他会把你当午餐嗑掉
He's gonna eat you for lunch.
她绝不会信任我们
She's never gonna trust us.
不能怪她,情报来源就是圈套
I can't blame her. The tip off was a trap.
有人把我们当傀儡把玩
Someone's got us dancing like marionettes.
正如莫西斯所说
Just like Moses called it.
没错
Yeah.
他会射杀副总统
He will take a shot at the V.P.
那是特勤局的问题
That's a problem for the Secret Service.
莫西斯会摧毁他们
Moses'll take them apart.
把我安插在他们的勤务中
Plug me into their detail.
没问题
You got it.
那她呢？
What about her？
我会留她在身边
I'll keep her close.
受到保护,不列纪录
Protected. Off the grid.
我藏了一些家伙
I put a few things away.
以防万一
Just in case. You know.
法兰克
Frank.
瑞典冲锋枪
Swedish K.
这可猛了
Now that is exciting.
炸药
Explosives？
不输火箭榴弹
Just past the RPGs.
我爱死你了
I love you, man.
别客气
Make yourself at home.
副总统会很爱这个
Oh, the Vice President's gonna love this.
芝加哥
也很开心见到你
Nice to see you, too.
“史坦登副总统”
谢谢
Thank you.
很抱歉
Oh. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
我真笨
Silly.
谢了,女士
Thanks, ma'am.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
不客气
You're welcome.
欢迎,布朗夫人
Welcome, Ms. Brown.
很高兴您参加胜利基金会盛宴
It's a pleasure to have you at our Victory Fund Gala.
我十分期待
Oh, I'm so looking forward to it.
副总统预备入场
Raptor' s cleared for entry.
您先请,副总统先生
After you, Mister Vice President.
真正的战争英雄
great American, a true war hero,
出色的朋友及杰出的领袖
a fabulous friend and a wonderful leader.
我万分喜悦向大家介绍
And so it is with great pleasure I introduce to you,
罗勃史坦登副总统
Vice President Robert Stanton.
谢谢,各位,很感谢你们的光临
Thank you, thank you everybody. Thank you so much for being here.
我会说得简短又明确
I'm gonna keep this short and sweet
免得你们听烦不签承诺的支票
so you'll actually write those checks you've been promising.
不过说真的,很开心能见到大家
Seriously, though, great to see you all.
送我们进入白宫的美好人们
It's the wonderful group of people here tonight
今晚齐聚一堂
that got us into the White House in the first place.
我相信这群美好人们
And I believe it's this wonderful group of people
会使我们留在白宫长长久久
who will keep us there for a long, long time！
我的好友们
My good friends, I'm proud to announce that
我很自豪宣布成立考察委员会
I will be forming an exploratory committee
主要目标是寻求总统职务提名
with the primary goal of seeking a nomination for the Presidency.
“史坦登竞选总统”
我们已一起踏上伟大的旅程
We've had a great, a great journey together.
不过我坚决相信未来会更好
But I firmly believe that the best is still to come.
天佑各位
God bless ya all.
天佑美国
God bless America！
你好,小兔子
Hello, bunny.
你这种行为可能会害死自己
Moves like that could get you killed.
你今晚的灿烂几乎使我出神
Your radiance tonight renders me almost speechless.
几乎
Almost.
你咧嘴在笑什么？
What are you grinning at？
我始终梦想暗杀美国总统
Mm. I've always dreamed of killing an American President.
是副总统
Vice President.
随便啦
Whatever.
再度把你抱入怀中,我欣喜若狂
Having you in my arms once again, I get carried away.
真的？
Really？
告诉我你爱我
Tell me you love me.
那是前尘往事了,伊凡
It's been a long time, Ivan.
眨眼之间
Blink of an eye.
伊凡
Ivan. Hmm？
音乐停了
The music has stopped.
是吗？
Is it？
那要干活了
Ah. To work, then.
伊凡！
Ivan！
你有闻到吗？
Do you smell that？
这一区禁止进入
This area is off limits.
不,没问题的
No, it's fine, it's fine.
你必须回去
You'll have to turn around.
不,没问题的
No, no. No, it's fine.
我确定我获准进入
It's alright. I'm sure I'm allowed.
你必须回去上面,女士
You'll have to go back up, ma'am,
否则我只能威胁你听命
or I'll have to treat you as a threat.
放马过来啊
Where exactly is the threat？
很高兴见到你
Good to see you.
我的天啊
Oh, my God！
毒气！我闻到毒气！
Gas！ I smell gas！
毒气！毒气！毒气！
Gas！ Gas！ Gas！
毒气！
Gaaaaaas！
让开
Stand aside.
主要出口受阻,走第二通道
Primary exit blocked. Secondary, move.
快走…！
Move！ Move！ Move！ Move！
让我出去
Let me out of here！
快走
他们用什么鬼武器？
What the hell are they using？
回来北楼梯间这里,马上！
Get back up in here to the north stairwell, now！
好耶
Ah, yes.
快上另一台礼车,我会掩护你
Move to the other limo. I'll cover you.
我们得走了,赶快！赶快！
We have to go. Now！ Now！
从后方接近目标
Approaching target from the rear.
外面！
Outside！
特勤局,大家趴下！
Secret Service, everybody down！
掩护我们,我们要离开了
Cover us！ We're moving now！
快点！快走！
Come on！ Move！
我记得特勤局更有料
I remember the Secret Service being tougher.
我也是
Me, too.
好了？
Okay？
好了
Yeah.
马文！
Marvin.
混蛋！
Fuckers！
快到了
Almost there.
马文
Marvin.
我们得走了
We gotta move.
你自己走,我帮不上忙了
You're on your own. I'm no use anymore.
祝好运,快去
Good luck. Go on.
快走
Let's move！
副总统,你中枪了吗？
- Are you hit, sir？ - I'm fine！
你中枪了吗？
- Are you hit？！ - I'm fine！
我没事！快把我送出这里
Just get me the hell out of here.
或许…
Perhaps…
我能派上用场？
I could be of assistance？
我爱你
I love you.
我知道
I know.
别动！
Freeze！
搞什么
What the-？
快跑！快跑！
Go！ Go！
快跑！
Go！
上车
Get in！
快开走！
Go, go, go！
阻止那台车,快阻止！
Stop the car！ Stop！
不准停车,继续开
Don't you dare stop！ You keep going！
停车！
Pull over！
我要知道这一切是怎么回事！
I wanna know what the hell that was all about！
柏巴赫！
- Burbacher！
甩开他！
- Get him off！
停车！
Pull over！
副总统安全了
Raptor is secure.
你是谁？
Who are you？
你下令杀掉的人之一
One of the men you ordered killed.
我不懂你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
瓜地马拉
Guatemala.
我在那里
I was there.
好吧…
Well…
我相信我们能达成协议
I'm sure we can negotiate something.
开始回想起来了吗？
Starting to come back to you now？
如果你是寻求报复…
If you're looking for revenge…
这不是报复
This is not about revenge.
你要杀了我？
Are you gonna kill me？
不只你
Not just you.
喂？
Yeah？
我在艾文斯顿发电厂
I'm at the Evanston power plant.
你有15分钟能把莎拉带来给我
You have 15 minutes to bring me Sarah.
否则我杀了副总统
Or I kill the Vice President.
他刚连络我,他要那女人
He just made contact. He wants the girl.
艾文斯顿发电厂,15分钟
Evanston Power Station. 15 minutes.
你最好通知特勤局
You better alert Secret Service.
收到
Copy that.
特勤局在途中
Secret Service is en route.
好,起来
Alright, come on.
莎拉在哪里？
Where's Sarah？
她在路上
She's on her way.
结束了,法兰克
It's over, Frank.
你随时会遭受天罗地网的攻击
Any minute the whole world is gonna drop on you.
等着瞧
We'll see.
嗨,硬汉
Hey, tough guy.
很惊讶见到我？
Surprised to see me？
搞什么鬼？
What the hell's this？
亚历山大
Alex…
满足他的一切要求吧
just give him what he wants.
我无法再伪装了
I can't do this anymore.
你下令这些暗杀行动,不是我
You ordered these killings, not me.
我不想再牵扯这件事了
I don't want to have anything to do with this anymore.
你对我开枪
You shot me.
闭嘴
Shut up.
我喜欢看你当英雄
I loved watching you bein' a good guy.
为祖国卖命
Kickin' ass for your country.
这显示你严重缺乏前瞻性
It showed a spectacular lack of vision.
释放那女人
The girl goes free.
用你的枪交换
That'll cost you a gun.
一命换一命
A life for a life.
我撕掉所有支票
I tore up all those checks.
我知道
I know.
我只想跟你说话
I just wanted to talk to you.
库伯
Cooper…
把他上铐
cuff him.
威尔克斯跟我说你前途看好
Wilkes told me you had promise.
好,情况如下
Okay. Here's how it goes.
莫西斯射杀副总统
Moses just shot the VP.
你杀了他和那女人
You kill him and the girl…
然后你会当上中情局局长
and you're head of the CIA.
库伯
Cooper…
这是必然的结果
this is gonna happen either way.
去你的,辛西亚
Fuck you, Cynthia.
谢了
Thanks.
你能搞定吗？
This gonna be a problem？
没问题
No.
包在我身上
I got it…
欧吉桑
Grandpa.
满意了？
Feel better now？
是啊
Yeah.
想吃煎饼吗？
Wanna get pancakes？
太神了,全解决了
Can you believe it？ It all worked out.
一定很快会有衰事发生
Something bad is gonna happen very soon.
或许不会,你们瞧
Maybe not. Wait a second.
没人在追我们
Nobody's chasin' us.
没人想杀我们
No one's trying to kill us.
我想我们生活重回轨道了
I think we just got our lives back.
几乎
Almost.
你仍欠我一次人情
You still owe me a small favor.
伊凡！
Oh, Ivan！
他真不会看场合说话
His timing is terrible.
你要还他人情？
You gave a favor to him？
只是摩尔多瓦的小核武问题
Just a tiny little nuclear problem in Moldova.
我们能去吗？
Can we go？
好,没问题
Yes. We can go.
“故事完”
我说过会有衰事发生
I told you something bad was gonna happen.
洋装穿好
Keep your dress on.
摩尔多瓦烂透了
Moldova sucks.
摩尔多瓦烂透了！
Moldova sucks！
下次,你马子能穿这洋装
Next time, your girlfriend can wear the dress.
“摩尔多瓦捎来的问候”
“后会有期”